<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<ParkList>
    <Park>
        <Name>Aaron</Name>
        <Size>116.74</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>49.758122</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-92.65349</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>May 20, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>September 18, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>https://www.ontarioparks.com/park/aaron</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Car Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>The campground offers almost 100 campsites, one-third of which have electricity.  Campsites can accommodate equipment ranging from tents only to large trailers.  Amenities such as water taps, comfort stations and laundry facilities are close by.  Swimming, boating, great fishing and hiking are only a short distance away.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Group Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Aaron has one group campsite.  The site accommodates 15 to 50 people.  Water taps and vault toilets are on site. The area is within walking distance of a comfort station, the beach and hiking trails.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Biking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Biking is a popular way to wander through Aaron and view the Eastern White Cedars that line the campground roads. Children are reminded to wear a helmet when biking.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Birding</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Many bird species and migratory waterfall call Aaron home.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Boating</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Boating is permitted on Thunder Lake but please take care when there are high winds; this open lake can get very choppy.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Canoeing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Aaron is located on the shores of Thunder Lake.  Spend the day exploring by canoe. Canoes are available for rent at the Park Office. Aaron can also be used as a starting point for several major canoe routes.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>The lakes in and around the park teem with Northern Pike, walleye and Lake Trout. A fish-cleaning station with lights, running water and cutting tables is located by the boat launch.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Hiking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Aspen Trail - 2km, moderate  
The Aspen Trail will introduce you to stands of boreal forest consisting of aspen, birch, Jack Pine, Balsam Fir and spruce trees. Walk through the remnants of the terrific wind storm of 1973 and over bare rock surfaces scarred by glaciers which melted 10 to 15 thousand years ago! Look for signs of White-tailed Deer, such as browsed branches, tracks and pellets. All the while you will be entertained by Aaron's 26 species of warblers, as well as other boreal songbirds.

Eastern White Cedar Trail - 1.2 km loop, easy
A stroll down this trail will help you appreciate the history and ecology of Aaron. You will walk through large, historic stands of trees, hike along the shores and wetlands of Thunder Lake and climb up a slope to a clay plain. See how many species of amphibians, mammals, birds, trees, flowers, lichens, and mosses you can spot along the way.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Aaron has two sandy beaches for swimmers that are located on the east and west sides of the park.  Parking, picnic tables and toilet facilities are conveniently located. Please note that there are no lifeguards posted at the beaches.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Barrier Free</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Barrier-free access is available at the comfort station.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Boat Launch</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>A boat launch is located by the fish cleaning hut.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Comfort Station(s)</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>A comfort station with showers and flush toilets is located in the main campground.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Aaron is a perfect day destination for visitors from the Dryden area.  The day-use area has a beach, large grassy play area, playground, picnic shelter, water taps and vault toilets.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Flush Toilets</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Flush toilets are found in various locations throughout the park, including the comfort station in the main campground.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Laundromat</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Laundry facilities can be found at the comfort station in the main campground.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Park Store</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Located in the Park Office, the store features clothing items, souvenirs, camper supplies, ice and firewood.

Groceries are available outside of the park in Dryden, 11 km west of the park on Highway 17.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Picnic Shelters</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>There is one picnic shelter in the day-use area of the park and it is available on a first-come first-served basis.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Rentals</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Canoes and kayaks are available for rent at the Park Office. Personal Floatation Devices (PFDs) are also available for loan with a $25 refundable deposit.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
    <Park>
        <Name>Arrowhead</Name>
        <Size>1237.00</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>45.3915</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-79.2140</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>May 13, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>October 11, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>http://ontarioparks.com/park/arrowhead</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Car Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Arrowhead offers camping in three campgrounds: Roe, East River and Lumby.

Roe Campground generally offers the most private, well-drained sites. The beach near this campground is less crowded and offers great access for fishing.

East River Campground is great for RVs, especially along Road 10. It is also closest to Stubbs Falls - a wonderful area to explore. The beach here is also a designated day use beach so tends to be busier.

Lumby is divided into two sections: north and south and they are quite similar. Forest cover in Lumby Campground is mixed deciduous forest. It offers great sites for tent trailers and tents. The dog beach is located nearest to the north Lumby Campground.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Roofed Accommodation</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Arrowhead has 6 camp cabins. The camp cabin is a rustic one room cabin with a rustic wood interior. The cabin sleeps five on a queen bed and double/single bunk bed.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Biking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Arrowhead has two moderately challenging mountain bike trails - the 4.5 km Arrowhead Lake Trail and the 3 km Lookout Trail.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Birding</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Several species of birds make Arrowhead their home in the spring and summer months, before migrating south for the winter. A bird list is available at the main gate.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Boating</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Motorized boats (including electric motors) are prohibited on Arrowhead and Mayflower lakes. Canoes are ideal for exploring the shorelines and viewing the wildlife of these lakes.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Canoeing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Be aware of weather conditions before going out as well as making sure you wear a personal floatation device (PFD) at all times.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Mayflower Lake is stocked with Rainbow Trout. Arrowhead Lake is good for Small Mouth Bass. A valid fishing license and outdoors card is required.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Hiking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Beaver Meadow Trail - 7 km (2 hours) moderate 
Arrowhead's longest trail passes Porcupine Bluffs, the remnant shoreline of a huge ancient lake. The bluffs are easily visible in the spring and fall but are hidden during the leafy summer months. The trail circles a large beaver pond with large rafts of cattails where you might see otter, moose, Great Blue Heron, Tree Swallows and, of course, beavers. Near the end, the trail crosses a field and you can see evidence of the once successful Oke homestead-old fence lines, building foundations and domestic plants such as rhubarb and apple trees.

Big Bend Lookout - easy 
This short walk from the parking lot on Roe Campground Road leads to a panoramic view of the meandering Big East River and the surrounding Muskoka terrain.

Homesteaders Trail - 3 km (1 hour) moderate
In the 1870s, homesteaders cleared this area. Take this trail across moderately rugged terrain and see traces of abandoned farm fields now reclaimed by young forest.

Mayflower Lake Trail - 1 km (30 minutes) moderate 
Ten thousand years ago, Mayflower Lake was a small bay in a large glacial lake. Today it is a small, deep, spring-fed lake. Its cold, clear waters provide ideal habitat for cold water fish such as Rainbow Trout. This trail has several lengthy climbs and descents over the hills surrounding Mayflower Lake and can be muddy, so wear your hiking boots.

Stubb's Falls Trail - 2 km (45 minutes) easy 
Take this trail in early spring when wildflowers and songbirds will be your reward. At Stubb's Falls, the Little East River rushes down a rock chute. Stop here for a pleasant respite.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Natural Heritage Education</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Park staff offer weekly educational programs for children and adults from early July to Labour Day. They include nature and historical walks, evening programs with guest speakers and videos, and children's crafts and games.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>There are three quiet, clean, sandy beaches with change facilities that back into birch groves. Please note: there are no lifeguards posted at the beaches and pets are not permitted.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Winter Activities</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>The main park road and three parking lots are kept open for winter visitors and to host major events including the Annual Muskoka Loppet (http://arrowheadnordic.ca), elementary school races and much more. In the winter, Arrowhead grooms and maintains more than 33 km of cross-country ski trails that are designed for classic skiing or skate skiing. Check the current trail conditions in the ski report. Each trail is rated for difficulty and ranges from beginner to expert. The park offers a variety of hiking/snowshoeing trails as well as a skating rink and skating trail. There are two warm-up shelters and an open fire pit at the top of the tubing hill! (Tubes provided).</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Barrier Free</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>There are barrier free showers and washrooms stalls at all comfort stations.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Comfort Station(s)</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>There are three comfort stations (complete with showers and flush toilets) located centrally in each campground.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Picnic areas can be found along the beaches.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Flush Toilets</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>All comfort stations are equipped with flush toilets. All privies in Roe Campground and many in East River Campground have flush toilets.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Park Store</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The Park Store sells groceries, snacks, candy, locally baked goods, Kawartha Dairy products, ice cream, park souvenirs and camping supplies. It is open from May until October (Thanksgiving weekend)</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Picnic Shelters</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>A group picnic shelter in the day-use area accommodates 50 - 100 people and can be reserved for birthday parties, reunions, gatherings or any other special event. Reservations can be made by calling the Park Office Monday - Friday, starting in April.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Rentals</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>In the summer months: canoes, kayaks and bicycles can be rented from the Beach Information Building at the day-use beach. There are also PFDs and helmets available to rent. In the winter months the main gate rents cross-country ski equipment, snowshoes and skates.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
        <Park>
        <Name>Awenda</Name>
        <Size>2915.00</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>44.843699</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-80.002699</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>May 13, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>October 11, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>http://ontarioparks.com/park/awenda</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Car Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Awenda offers camping in six campgrounds. Sites are shaded beneath Sugar Maples and Red Oaks and are spaced further apart than many other provincial parks. All of the sites in Wolf and some sites in Hawk Campground offer electrical hook-ups. Deer and Bear Campgrounds are designated radio-free while Snake Campground is both radio-free and dog-free.

All six campgrounds are serviced by drinking water taps, vault toilets and a central comfort station complete with flush toilets and showers. Laundry facilities are included at the comfort stations in Turtle, Hawk and Bear Campgrounds.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Dog-Free Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>All campsites in Snake Campground are dog-free and radio-free.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Group Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Awenda offers three group campsites.  These sites are designated for tents only and are for groups ranging in size from a minimum of 20 to a maximum of 40 people.  Each site is serviced with a water tap, central fire pit, several picnic tables and vault toilets.  To reserve, call the park directly at 705-549-2231.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Radio-Free Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>All campsites in Bear, Deer and Snake Campgrounds are radio-free.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Roofed Accommodation</CampType>
                <CampDescription>The Stone Cottage at Awenda is located directly on the shores of Georgian Bay providing guests with beautiful sunsets and unobstructed views of Giants Tomb, Hope, Beckwith and Christian Islands. This 1,000 square foot refurbished cottage has an exterior constructed of fieldstone and mortar with a warm inviting interior finished entirely in White and Red Pine.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Biking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Several kilometers of park roads are available for cyclists.

Bikes are also allowed on the Beach, Bluff and Brule Trails. Since these are multi-use trails, racing is not permitted and cyclists must yield to pedestrians and hikers.

Cyclists are encouraged to respect and protect the often sensitive environments that these trails pass through by riding only on the designated trail surface.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Birding</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Awenda is home to at least 120 breeding bird species. The park's upland forests provide a critical habitat refuge for the endangered Cerulean Warbler.

The park's trails, lakes, shorelines, fens, bogs and campgrounds offer a mix of habitat for a variety of viewing opportunities and discovery.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Boating</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Boating enthusiasts will find plenty of room to investigate Georgian Bay. Because of its size and exposed area, Georgian Bay winds can be unpredictable and quick to rise, so use appropriate caution.

The closest boat launch facilities are in Penetanguishene. Outboard motors are not allowed on Kettle's Lake.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Canoeing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Awenda's quiet and scenic Kettle's Lake is an excellent location for putting in your own canoe or one you rent from the park. This small, motorboat free lake is ideally suited for the novice paddler or nature enthusiast.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Bass, Northern Pike, pickerel and smaller panfish are commonly found in the waters between Awenda and Giant's Tomb Island. Bass and panfish are also found in Kettle's Lake.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Hiking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Awenda offers a nice variety of looped and linear, easy to moderate trails and range from 1 to 13 km in length. One trail provides barrier-free access.

Beach Trail - 4 km return (1.5 hours) linear, easy
This trail takes hikers along the Georgian Bay shoreline. Giant's Tomb Island is visible from the trail. The contrast between the dry oak-maple forest of the campgrounds and the low, wet birch-cedar-hemlock forest below the bluff can be seen.

Beaver Pond Trail - 1 km (30 minutes) loop, easy, barrier free
Located in a nature reserve zone most of this trail is a boardwalk that takes you through an area altered by past and present beaver activity. Along the way you will see the remains of both a building and a bridge from the early logging days. The area also offers views of the dominant Nipissing bluff as well as excellent opportunities for viewing wildlife, wildflowers and many species of birds.

Bluff Trail - 13 km (3.5 hours) loop, moderate
This circular trail can be accessed from a number of locations within the park. It travels partly along a high bluff and partly through a low wetland. Views of Georgian Bay from sections of this trail are spectacular, especially during the late autumn, early spring leaf- free season.

Nipissing Trail - 1 km return (30 minutes) linear, moderate
The Nipissing Bluff is the dominant glacial feature in Awenda. It is a raised beach created 5,500 years ago by glacial Lake Nipissing. Today a 155 step staircase allows hikers to easily descend 32 metres down the face of the bluff, at times providing you with the sensation of being part of the forest canopy.

Brule Trail - 4 km return (1.5 hours) linear, easy
This trail passes through a portion of the park's upland mixed deciduous forest. Lumbering and fires have obliterated the White Pine stands so that the majority of trees are now Sugar Maple and Red Oak. Lumbering on the peninsula was at its peak in the late 1800s. Since then the forest has been allowed to revert to its natural state but the White Pine has been unable to fully re-establish itself.

Robitaille Homestead Trail - 3 km return (1hour) linear, easy
Hikers follow this trail to an ancient dune system. The age of these sand dunes has been estimated at 11,500 years, from the time of the last glacial retreat. The dunes are a very fragile environment and we ask that you do not climb the hillside, stand on the edge of the bluff or climb down the bluff. This will allow plants to re-establish themselves and will help us preserve this area for future park visitors. On the way to the dunes, this trail passes an abandoned farmstead originally built in 1902. Remains of the stone foundations and fence rows can still be seen.

Wendat Trail - 5 km (2 hours) loop, easy
This trail begins at Kettle's Lake. This lake is thought to be a kettle lake formed by the gradual melting of a large buried piece of ice left by retreating glaciers. Today, this area is a favoured nesting spot for the Red-winged Blackbird and the Great Blue Heron is often seen in the swamps around the lake. The trail passes the foundations of the Brabant farmstead house and barn. Attempts to farm this area in the 1930s and 40s failed due to the poor, sandy soil.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Natural Heritage Education</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Awenda offers a wide variety of programs for enthusiasts of all ages. Regularly scheduled guided hikes, children's programs, special events and evening programs occur from late June to early fall featuring the unique cultural history and the biology of the park.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Awenda features several beautiful and natural beaches on the Georgian Bay shoreline within driving distance from the campgrounds. The most protected and sandiest beach area is at Methodist Point Bay (Third Beach). Swimmers are reminded that that there are no lifeguards at the beaches.

For a refundable deposit, you can borrow a properly fitted personal floatation device (PFD) during your stay at Awenda.

Awenda has designated a stretch of its scenic Georgian Bay shoreline as a Pet Beach. This is the only public beach in the park where pets are permitted. However they still must be kept on a two metre leash and it is the owner's responsibility to clean up after them.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Winter Activities</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>The park is not open for camping, but the trails and forests are available as a backcountry style experience for the more adventuresome ski and snowshoe enthusiast. 

Trails begin at the Trail Centre, a cozy wood heated log cabin. Although 17 kilometres of ski trail are often packed and set with a single track, be prepared to occasionally track your own trails due to the backcountry intent of this self-use winter program.

Snowshoeing is popular through the park's many hectares of open bush; however there are no designated snowshoe trails.

Dogs are not permitted on winter trails and visitors must provide their own equipment as rentals are not available.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Barrier Free</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Awenda's six comfort stations are barrier-free as is the park amphitheatre.

Each campground has a designated barrier-free campsite (sites #24, #96, #141, #193, #215, and #295), with a modified picnic table, easy access to drinking water and the comfort station.

The vault toilets/outhouses in Wolf and Snake Campgrounds are barrier-free as are some vault toilets in Bear and Deer Campgrounds.

The First Beach area is serviced by three barrier-free vault toilets, viewing platform and the one kilometre Beaver Pond Trail and boardwalk. The Kettle's Landing day-use area has a barrier-free vault toilet, boardwalk, picnic and viewing area. The park also has a free non-motorized all-terrain wheelchair service.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Comfort Station(s)</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Comfort stations, complete with accessible showers and flush toilets are available in each of the park's six campgrounds: Turtle, Hawk, Bear, Deer, Wolf and Snake.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Relaxing picnicking opportunities are available at Kettle's Lake and also at the park's many beaches, with a view of Georgian Bay and Giant's Tomb Island. In this natural setting, tables are limited, so remember to bring a picnic blanket.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Flush Toilets</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Available only at the comfort stations located in each campground.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Laundromat</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Laundry facilities are available at the comfort stations in Turtle, Hawk and Bear Campgrounds.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Park Store</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Located adjacent to the Campground Office the Park Store is your most convenient location for basic food staples, ice cream treats, quality souvenirs, field guides, ice, some camping supplies and a propane cylinder exchange service.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Picnic Shelters</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>A large covered picnic shelter is available at the Trail/Activity Centre area when it is not being used for interpretive programs.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Rentals</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Visitors can borrow a properly fitted Personal Floatation Device (PFD) with a $25 refundable deposit. Staff can provide additional information and can outfit you with a PFD at the Campground Office.

Electrical extension cords for trailer units are also available for a daily or weekly fee.

Canoes, complete with paddles and PFDs, are available to rent, by the hour or the half day, for use on Kettle's Lake. Canoe rentals are available from late June to Labour Day.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
        <Park>
        <Name>Balsam Lake</Name>
        <Size>448.81</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>44.62555</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-78.85738</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>May 13, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>October 11, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>http://ontarioparks.com/park/balsamlake</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Car Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Balsam Lake has a range of campsites with and without electricity for tents and RVs. For a private, natural experience car access walk-in sites are also available. Campsites may be reserved from the second Friday in May through to the Thanksgiving weekend. Reservations are accepted five months in advance of arrival - reserve early to avoid disappointment.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Dog-Free Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Dog free camping is available at the six Eco (walk-in) sites.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Group Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>At Balsam Lake there are three Group Camping sites serviced with vault privies and drinking water. The use of the site is for non-profit youth groups only.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Radio-Free Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Eco (walk-in) sites, Cedar Grove, Mapleview and Hawthorne Valley campgrounds are now radio-free.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Walk-In Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Six radio-free, pet free, Eco (walk-in) campsites are available.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Roofed Accommodation</CampType>
                <CampDescription>This fully furnished 4-bedroom cottage is located close to the water and is fully equipped with: three queen and two single beds, propane furnace with central air, refrigerator, stove, microwave oven, toaster oven, pop corn popper, coffee maker, dishwasher, pots, dishes, pans, cutlery, TV, DVD Player, telephone (with modem jack), BBQ, outdoor fire pit, picnic table, game tables, dart board and a coin operated washer and dryer.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Biking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Cycle on campground roads and over 10 km of local cottage roads (adjacent to the park).</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Birding</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Find a wide range of birds from hummingbirds, Blue birds, cardinals, Northern orioles, Pileated woodpeckers, hawks, osprey and owls. Relax to the call of the loon.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Boating</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Canoes, kayaks and paddle boats are available to rent on the south end of the beach. Personal floatation devices (PFDs) are supplied for all rentals. A boat launch and boat trailer parking is available.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Canoeing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Explore the shores of Balsam Lake.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Fish for Walleye, Muskellunge, Large and Small Mouth Bass</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Hiking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Lookout Trail - 2.6 km (1.5 hours) walk through eskers and kames formed over 10,000 years ago from the Wisconsin Glacier. Enjoy a panoramic view of the surrounding area.

Plantation Trail - 4.2 km (2 hours) - a moderate forest trek with both natural and pioneer highlights.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Natural Heritage Education</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Regularly scheduled programs and events including excellent children's programs are available during the summer season.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>The clean, sandy beach is marked with buoys. Please note that there are no lifeguards posted.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Boat Launch</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Docking and trailer parking is available.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>There is a shady, grassed area with an excellent view of the lake and a children's playground.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Laundromat</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Coin operated washers and dryers are available at our four comfort stations.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Park Store</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The park gift shop offers clothing items, souvenirs, ice, ice cream, coffee and firewood. Groceries are available just outside the park at The Park Store and in the town of Coboconk.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Pet Exercise Area</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Located at canoe launch.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Picnic Shelters</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>There are three large picnic shelters located near the main beach area. The shelters maybe reserved by calling the park at (705)-454-3324 (not available to reserve on holiday weekends).</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Rentals</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Canoes, kayaks and paddle boats are available to rent on the beach.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
        <Park>
        <Name>Bass Lake</Name>
        <Size>65.00</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>44.601000</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-79.482900</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>May 13, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>September 25, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>http://ontarioparks.com/park/basslake</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Car Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Bass Lake's car camping consists of four different campgrounds: Lakeview, Eastside, Cedar, and Hilltop. Each campground has access to washrooms and three of our four campgrounds have a shower building located inside the campground. Lakeview is a non-electrical campground. There is a fully serviced washroom and shower building located in this campground with smaller washrooms located throughout.

Cedar Campground is also a non-electrical campground and is the closest campground to our day-use and waterfront area. This campground does not have a shower building but does have vault washrooms located close by. Showers can be accessed in adjacent campgrounds.

Hilltop Campground is features both electrical and non-electrical campsites.  This campground has access to the shower building in Eastside Campground and has washrooms located throughout.

Eastside Campground is a fully electrical campground and campsites #5 and #6 are barrier free and fully reservable. Campsite #215 is another of our barrier-free sites located in Lakeview Campground but is available on a first-come first-served basis only.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Group Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Bass Lake has three group camping areas available for reservation from the Friday of the Victoria Day weekend until Labour Day.  After Labour Day the group camping areas are available on a first-come first-served basis only. 

Our group campsites consist of two large areas that will accommodate up to a maximum of 60 people including children and one smaller area that will accommodate up to maximum of 40 people including children. 

Electricity is not available at our group sites.  Each site has a small parking lot available for campers and there are additional parking lots located throughout the park.  The group sites have vault washrooms and drinking water taps. Shower buildings are accessible in adjacent campgrounds.  The sites are approximately a 10 minute walk from our day-use and beach area along the park walking trail. </CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Biking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Part of our hiking trail is paved and bicycle friendly. Visitors are also welcome to bike on park roads.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Boating</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>The park has a boat launch can accommodate a boat up to 20 feet. There are alos docks for temporary docking.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Canoeing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Canoe rentals are available at the park store.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Sportfishing for bass is good and the season starts on the last Saturday of June each year.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Hiking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>You can appreciate some of the natural and historic points of interest on our 2.8 km trail, which winds its way through a variety of habitats. Along the way uncover the park's history with the Rowe Homestead, a working farm for more than 100 years, the effects of glaciers from 10,000 years ago and the importance of the next generation of flora and fauna. You will also find that the first half kilometre of trail, which begins at our beach parking lot, has been paved making it accessible for everyon. We have trail guides available at our Park Registration Building.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Shallow, clear water makes Bass Lake perfect for swimming.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Winter Activities</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Bass Lake Provincial Park offers a small program for outdoor winter enthusiasts. From our fall closing date (fourth Sunday in September) through to our spring operating season in May, visitors can access the park by walking in, using a pay and park coin-only system, to enjoy our 4.0 km network of groomed cross-country ski trails. We also groom a hiking trail for those that prefer to walk or snowshoe instead of ski.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Barrier Free</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Barrier-free access is available at all comfort stations and we offer two barrier-free electrical sites in Eastside Campground and one non-electrical barrier-free site campsite in Lakeview Campground. Campsites #5 and #6 in Eastside Campground are available for reservation through the Ontario Parks website and call centre. Campsite #215 in Lakeview Campground is available on a first-come first- served basis only. A portion of our hiking trail is paved for barrier-free access and all of our visitor buildings are barrier-free as well.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Boat Launch</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Bass Lake Provincial Park has a boat launch that is available for use from the second Friday in May through to the third Sunday in September. The cost of using the boat launch is included in the campsite fee and seasonal permit fee. If you are not camping in the park, you must purchase a Daily Vehicle Permit to access the boat launch.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Comfort Station(s)</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>All of Bass Lake's campgrounds, with the exception of Cedar Campground offer fully serviced comfort stations with showers and flush toilets.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>During the summer months, our day-use area is available upon purchase of a valid day-use permit, summer pass, annual pass or if you have a valid camping permit.  During the winter months, access to the park is available by walk-in only using a pay and park, coin only system.  No alcohol is permitted in our day-use area. If you are bringing pets, they must be leashed at all times, including during our off-season and they are not permitted on the beach.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Flush Toilets</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Flush toilets are located in the comfort stations found in Lakeview, Eastside and Hilltop Campgrounds. Smaller washrooms are located throughout the park.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Park Store</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The park has a small store that is open from the last weekend in June until Labour Day. It features items such as ice cream, chips, candy, beverages, and Ontario Parks Merchandise.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Picnic Shelters</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Bass Lake has three picnic shelters available for reservation from the Friday of the Victoria Day weekend until Labour Day. After Labour Day the picnic shelters are available on a first-come first-served basis only. We have one large picnic shelter that will accommodate up to 100 people and two smaller shelters that will accommodate up to 45 people each. Each shelter comes with the use of a charcoal barbeque and has enough picnic tables to accommodate maximum capacity. Alcohol is not permitted in our day-use area and this includes our picnic shelters. Parking is available within close proximity to each shelter and there are washrooms and drinking water taps nearby.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Rentals</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>We currently offer a small fleet of canoes, paddle boats and kayaks for rent on a first-come first-served basis from the end of June to Labour Day. A security deposit is required, (charged to a credit card with each rental) and you must be a minimum of 16 years of age to rent a boat. Each rental comes with all necessary equipment including Personal Floatation Devices, emergency kits and oars.

We also offer a Personal Floatation Device (PFD) loaner program where you can rent a PFD for a refundable $30.00 deposit for each jacket. PFDs are available at our Registration Office or our Park Store.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
        <Park>
        <Name>Batchawana</Name>
        <Size>169.03</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>46.944168</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-84.551017</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>May 13, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>October 10, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>http://ontarioparks.com/park/batchawana</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType></CampType>
                <CampDescription></CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Boating</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Boats must be carried into the water or driven to a launch east of the park at the mouth of the Batchawana River. Sudden squalls occur frequently and can be hazardous.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Rainbow trout, Northern Pike, Salmon, Lake Trout, and Walleye are all possible catches.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Batchawana Bay Provincial Park features a sandy beach that is the perfect setting for families. The water is shallow and protected and the warmest on the Lake Superior shoreline.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>A beach front area with picnic tables and vault toilets are available.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Picnic Shelters</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>There is one picnic shelter in the park that is available on a first-come first-served basis.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
        <Park>
        <Name>Biscotasi Lake</Name>
        <Size>12283.00</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>47.352455</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-81.997528</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>May 6, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>October 10, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>http://ontarioparks.com/park/biscotasilake</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Backcountry Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Interior camping only - 83 marked backcountry sites. All campsites are equipped with a fire pit and a box privy. There is a can and bottle ban in the park. All garbage is to be removed by the camper. Driftwood can be gathered for campfires.
Overnight camping is permitted at the Duke Lake access prior to starting your trip. Interior camping fees and rules apply.

There is a self-serve registration box and permits located at the Duke Lake access. Permits for other access points can be obtained by calling Chutes Provincial Park (705-865-2021) or one of the following permit issuers: 
Chutes Provincial Park - 705-865-2021 (year round)
Agnew Lake Lodge -   705-869-2239 (mid April to October)
Biscotasing General Store - 705-239-0830 (May to October)
Spanish River Outfitters - 705-919-2607 (mid April to October)
Windy Lake Provincial Park - 705-966-2315 (Victoria Day weekend in May - 
Labour Day in September)
Halfway Lake Provincial Park - 705-965-2702 (Victoria Day weekend in May - 
mid-September)</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Birding</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>The park supports abundant bird life: osprey, Bald Eagles, Belted Kingfishers and Great Blue Herons are often seen while fishing. Many species of songbirds nest in the forests along the river, including Black and White Warblers, Yellow Warblers and Ovenbirds.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Boating</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Motorboats are allowed on Biscotasi Lake and Agnew Lake.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Canoeing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>The Spanish River offers a number of paddling options:

East Branch:
Duke Lake to Agnew Lake - 145 km (8-10 days)
The Forks to The Elbow - 58 km (3 days)
The Elbow to Agnew Lake - 50 km (2-3 days)
*Sheahan to The Elbow - 40 km (2 days)

West Branch:
Biscotasi Lake to Agnew Lake - 164 km (8-10 days)
*Sinker Creek to Agnew Lake - 120 km (6-8 days)
Biscotasi Lake to The Elbow - 114 km (5-7 days)
Biscotasi Lake to Sheahan - 74 km (4 days)

*VIA Rail access only. A scenic train ride is a unique way to start your trip. The train will drop off and pick up paddlers and all their gear at various points along the river.

Canoeists and sea kayakers can paddle among the many islands that dot Biscotasi Lake and experience the vast country that was once home to Grey Owl, the famous conservationist. Two other large lakes are a very short portage from Biscotasi Lake; Ramsey Lake and Indian Lake have hundreds of kilometres of shoreline, bays and islands and when combined with Biscotasi it makes for a perfect kayaking and canoeing route for flatwater paddlers.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Many species of fish such as Walleye, Northern Pike, Lake and Brook Trout inhabit the many lakes and tributaries along the river.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Spanish River has no designated beaches but there are plenty of swimming opportunities.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Boat Launch</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>There is a public boat launch at the Duke Lake access. Boat launches are located at Biscotasing General Store and Agnew Lake Lodge (a launch fee applies at this location).</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The park is open for day-use. Permits for day-use are not required.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
        <Park>
        <Name>Blue Lake</Name>
        <Size>2314.00</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>49.904122</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-93.469178</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>May 20, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>September 18, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>http://ontarioparks.com/park/bluelake</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Car Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Blue Lake offers a range of car camping opportunities from private tent pads to pull through sites with parking areas. Half of the campsites offer electrical hook-up.  Amenities such as water taps, comfort stations and laundry facilities are close by.  Swimming, boating and the Visitor Centre are only a short distance away.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Group Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Blue Lake has two group campsites available.  The sites vary in size and can accommodate 40 to 140 people.  Water taps are nearby and vault toilets are either on site or close by.  A beach borders the group camping area. Both sites offer electrical hookup.

Call the park directly to reserve (807) 227-2601 (summer) or (807) 223-7535 (winter after 1st day in January).</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Roofed Accommodation</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Trailer Equipped Campsite</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Biking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Bicycles are a great way to explore the campground. They are permitted on park roads but not on the trail system.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Birding</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>The boreal forest is home to a variety of bird species. Often the Common Loon fills the evening sky with its mournful song as Chimney Swifts fly high above, snagging insects out of the air. Bald Eagles are common place as well as many forest dwelling song birds. Bird checklists are available at the Visitor Centre.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Boating</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Power boats are allowed on all lakes within Blue Lake Provincial Park but please be aware of non-motorized canoes, kayaks and sailboats.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Canoeing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Take a canoe out onto Blue Lake and explore for the afternoon or try a longer canoe adventure starting from the park.

Route 12 Blue Lake- 97 km loop, partially in the park, moderate, 5-7 days
This route features varied scenery, wildlife and sandy beaches. In the past, portages were used as trading routes to the Hudson Bay Post on Eagle Lake. There is also an abandoned Mica mine site on Cobble Lake.

Detailed maps and more canoe route information is available at the Blue Lake Park Office.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Blue Lake is a popular fishing lake for Lake Trout, Smallmouth Bass, and Northern Pike. Walleye and the elusive musky can be caught but are a challenge even for an experienced angler. Nearby Corner Lake and the Indian Lake chain are popular for walleye.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Hiking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Boulder Ridge Trail - 1 km, easy, 30 minutes
Walk through a forest created by fire, onto a ridge made by ice and over sands carried by rivers now dry. The Boulder Ridge Trail mixes past and present into a fascinating half hour stroll.

Goblin Lake Trail - 11 km, moderate, full day
For those with an adventurous streak, the Goblin Lake Trail follows the edge of Goblin Lake and explores the wilds of Northern Ontario the way our pioneers would have. Follow the directional signs carefully and always let someone know where you are hiking and when you expect to return. Bring a snack and plenty of water for this all day hike.

Rock Point Trail - 4km, moderate
This 4 km trail takes you through a variety of environments from cedar groves to Jack Pine ridges. As you will be hiking through varying terrain, be sure to wear appropriate foot wear. Your journey starts at the beaver pond and loops back to the campground near M road.

Spruce Fen Boardwalk Trail - 1 km, easy, barrier-free, 30 minutes
A fen is a fascinating world where land floats on water, plants eat animals and creatures of the water fly. The Spruce Fen Trail takes you through a Black Spruce fen and a beaver pond environment. Interpretive signs help describe these environments along the trail. To protect the fen, the trail is a boardwalk and is also wheelchair accessible.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Hunting</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Hunting is permitted in the Blue Lake park additions. Be sure to ask a Ministry of Natural Resources and Forestry representative of proper boundaries.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Natural Heritage Education</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>During the summer staff offer a variety of fun, interactive educational programs. Join a Park Naturalist as you explore the hiking trails, stop by the Visitor Centre to learn about the 1900s burn that made Blue Lake what it is today, bring your young campers to the children's programs and take the whole family to the evening campfires and slide shows!</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Blue Lake is renowned for its long sandy beaches and exceptionally clear, blue water. Summer fun in the water is what brings families to Blue Lake. A buoy line marks the swimming area.

Please note that the beach is not supervised by lifeguards. Pets and alcohol are prohibited on the beach.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Barrier Free</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Barriefree access is available at both comfort stations. There is also a wheelchair ramp at the day-use area. The 1 km Spruce Fen Trail is wheelchair accessible. We also have two campsites that are saved for campers who require barrier-free access.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Boat Launch</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>A boat launch is located at the north end of the beach and a dock is available for your convenience.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Comfort Station(s)</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Comfort stations with showers and flush toilets are centrally located in each of the park's campground.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The entire 1 km beach at Blue Lake is a popular day-use area. This sandy beach has buoyed swimming areas and shady areas with picnic tables, water taps and hibachis.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Flush Toilets</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Flush toilets are found in various locations throughout the campground and day-use area.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Laundromat</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Coin operated washers and dryers are located in both of Blue Lakes' comfort stations.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Park Store</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Located in the main entry station, the Blue Lake store sells basic camper needs and Ontario Parks' merchandise. The store features clothing items, souvenirs, books and ice cream.

Ice and groceries are available outside of the park in Vermilion Bay, nine km south of the park on Highway 17.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Pet Exercise Area</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Let your furry friend off-lead on this designated pet exercise area past the park emergency exit road.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Picnic Shelters</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>There is one picnic shelter in the park located at the center of the beach. The shelter is available on a first-come first-served basis. Group campsite #502 also has its own picnic shelter.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Rentals</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Canoes and kayaks are available for rent. Personal Floatation Devices (PFDs) are also available on loan with a $25 refundable deposit.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Visitor Centre</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Stop by the Visitor Centre, located in an old log cabin at the south end of the beach, to view displays of plant, rock and wildlife specimens. The cabin is one of the original cottages from the early days of Blue Lake campers.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
        <Park>
        <Name>Bon Echo</Name>
        <Size>8294.00</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>44.89720</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-77.20950</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>May 13, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>October 16, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>http://ontarioparks.com/park/bonecho</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Backcountry Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Abes and Essens - Overnight Hiking Trail
This trail features three loops of four, nine and 17 km. Five campsites are available along the trail for overnight stays.  Each campsite has a picnic table and tent space; toilets are nearby.

Canoe-in Camping
Twenty-five canoe-in campsites are located on Joeperry and Pearson Lakes.  A short canoe trip of 10 to 30 minutes will get you to your campsite.  At each campsite, you will find a picnic table, tent space and a toilet nearby.  Joeperry Lake has the added bonus of a sandy beach.

Note that the channel to Pearson Lake campsites may not be navigable when water levels are low.  Please check on current status with park staff.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Car Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Bon Echo offers car camping in two campgrounds; Mazinaw Lake and Hardwood Hill.

The Mazinaw Lake Campground has three camping loops; Sawmill Bay, Midway and Fairway.  Campsites on these loops can accommodate equipment ranging from tents only to large trailers.  Many campsites offer electrical hook-up.  Amenities such as water taps, comfort stations and laundry facilities are close by.  Swimming, boating and the Visitor Centre are only a short distance away.

For a semi-wilderness experience, you can camp in the maple-beech forest of the Hardwood Hill Campground.  Sites in Hardwood Hill can accommodate tents or tent-trailers.  Toilets are nearby and there is one comfort station to service the campground.  There are no electrical hook-ups.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Radio-Free Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>The Midway loop of the Mazinaw Lake Campground and Hardwood Hill Campground are radio-free.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Walk-In Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>If you prefer some distance from other campers and your car, consider a walk-in campsite.  Sawmill Bay Campground loop has five walk-in campsites located right on Mazinaw Lake.  The Hardwood Hill Campground has a walk-in loop with nine campsites.  Parking is approximately 100 to 300 metres from your campsite.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Roofed Accommodation</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Bon Echo has six camp cabins. The camp cabin is a rustic one room cabin with a rustic wood interior. The cabin sleeps five on a queen bed and double/single bunk bed.
                The Cabin on the Hill is a historic log cabin dating from the 1870s. It has been moved twice during its lifetime and is now located on a hill near the Visitor Centre. Guests staying at the cabin will enjoy a great view of Mazinaw Rock.
                Sawmill Bay Campground has an exiting new camping option:
Exploration Tents, soft-walled structures that can accommodate up to five people.
Two of Bon Echo's six yurts are located in the Sawmill Bay area of Mazinaw Lake Campground. A comfort station is nearby. The remainder are located near the South Beach.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Biking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Biking is permitted on park roads only.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Birding</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>The Peregrine Falcon, a threatened species in Ontario, is often seen nesting on Mazinaw Rock. Great Crested Flycatchers, Yellow-Bellied Sapsuckers, Common Loon, Turkey Vultures, kestrels and Red-Tailed Hawks are popular bird sightings. Bird checklists are available at the Friends Gift and Book Shop.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Boating</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Power boats are allowed on Mazinaw Lake but are prohibited on all other lakes in the park.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Canoeing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Kishkebus Canoe Route - 21 km (6 hours), loop, moderate to difficult
This day paddle takes you past Aboriginal pictographs to the still waters of the nature reserve on the east side of the park.  Please note: there is a 1.5 km portage.

Joeperry and Pearson Lakes
Spend a relaxing day paddling in motorboat free lakes or reserve one of the 25 backcountry campsites. There is a 500m portage from the parking lot to the launch. Joeperry Lake also features a natural sandy beach.

Mazinaw Lake
Launch your canoe or rent one at the lagoon and you can paddle on Mazinaw Lake. Head over to Mazinaw Rock to view one of Canada's largest visible collections of Aboriginal pictographs.

Mississippi River Canoe Route - 104 km (5 days), 17 portages, moderate
For more information on this route, contact the Mississippi Valley Conservation Authority</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Mazinaw Lake is a popular fishing lake for Lake Trout, Yellow Pickerel, Small and Large Mouth Bass, Lake Whitefish and Northern Pike.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Hiking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Abes and Essens Lake Trail - 3 interconnecting looped trails:  Clutes 3.5 km (1.5 hours); Essens Lake 9.6 km (4 hours) and Abes 17 km (7 hours) moderate to difficult.  
Some sections offer panoramic views that are particularly spectacular in fall.  Hike for a day or camp at one of the five campsites along the trail (campsite reservations required).

Bon Echo Creek Trail: 1 km (40 minutes), linear, easy
Take a leisurely walk along the Bon Echo Creek.

Cliff Top Trail - 1.5 km (1 hour), linear, moderate to difficult
This trail is only accessible by water. A ferry service (fees apply), will take you to the start of the trail. Canoe and kayak rentals are also available. Stairs and a pathway take hikers to the top of Mazinaw Rock to three observation decks overlooking the lake.

High Pines Trail - 1.7 km (1 hour), loop, moderate 
Hikers pass a variety of forest and wetland communities including tall pines, groves of hemlock and quiet forest ponds.

Shield Trail - 4.8 km (2 hours), loop, moderate 
Follow a section of the old Addington Road as it penetrates the rugged landscape of the Canadian Shield where you will see hardwood forests, cedar lowlands and a beaver swamp.

Pet Exercise Trail - 1.4 km (1 hour), loop, easy
Let your furry friend off-leash on this designated pet exercise trail.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Natural Heritage Education</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>During the summer park staff offer a variety of fun, interactive educational programs. Join a park naturalist as you explore the hiking trails and stop by the Visitor Centre to learn about the 1920s Bon Echo Inn. Attend a children's program or bring the whole family to the popular evening shows at the amphitheatre.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>There are three natural sand beaches recommended for swimming. The Main Beach is located in Lower Mazinaw Lake, South Beach is located in the Day-Use area, and North Beach is in Sawmill Bay campground. These beaches are marked with buoys. Please note: there are no lifeguards posted at the beaches and pets are not permitted.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Barrier Free</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>All comfort stations offer barrier-free access. There is also a wheelchair ramp at the day-use area, Gift Shop and Visitor Centre.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Boat Launch</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Boat launches are located near North Beach, the Lagoon, and along Bon Echo Creek.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Comfort Station(s)</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Comfort stations (complete with showers and flush toilets) are located in Hardwood Hill, Midway, Fairway and Sawmill Bay campgrounds and at the Day-Use area.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Main Beach and South Beach are popular day-use areas. Both have sandy beaches with buoyed swimming areas (but no lifeguards) and shady areas with picnic tables, hibachis, and water taps nearby.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Flush Toilets</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Flush toilets are found in various locations in Midway, Fairway and Sawmill Bay campgrounds, the Lagoon and the Day-Use area.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Laundromat</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Washers and dryers are available at comfort stations (fees apply).</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Park Store</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Greystones Gift and Book Shop, operated by the Friends of Bon Echo Park, is located in the historic Greystones building. The Shop features clothing items, souvenirs and books.

Ice and groceries are available outside of the park in Cloyne, seven km south of the park on Highway 41.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Picnic Shelters</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>There is one picnic shelter in the park located at the Lagoon. The shelter is available on a first-come first-served basis.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Rentals</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Canoes and kayaks are available for rent at the Lagoon.

Personal Floatation Devices (PFDs) are also available for loan with a refundable deposit.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Visitor Centre</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The park visitor centre is located in Dollywood, one of the original cottages from the Bon Echo Inn era. Learn more about the Aboriginal pictograph site, the history of the Inn and the wildlife in the park.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
        <Park>
        <Name>Bonnechere</Name>
        <Size>162.00</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>45.65729</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-77.57886</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>May 20, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>October 11, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>http://ontarioparks.com/park/bonnechere</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Car Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Bonnechere offers car camping in three campgrounds; Tall Pines, River Loop and Sandy Flats. Tall Pines and River Loop Campgrounds are within a five minute walk to swimming, the Visitor Centre and Park Store while Sandy Flats is a 10 minute walk to these amenities. All campgrounds provide access to a central comfort station, laundry facilities and water taps.

Tall Pines Campground consists of 60 campsites that are set among some spectacular White Pine trees that have survived the logging days. Campsites in Tall Pines campground can accommodate equipment ranging from tents only to large trailers. Twenty-four of these campsites offer electrical hook up.

Campsites in the River Loop Campground can accommodate tents only to small trailers. Electrical sites are not provided in this campground. Many of the campsites are located immediately adjacent to the Bonnechere River, providing direct access to water activities such as boating, canoeing, fishing and wildlife viewing. 

Sandy Flats is a radio-free campground that can accommodate tents to small trailers. Electrical sites are not provided in this campground. Sandy Flats Campground has a mini-comfort station which provides pedal flush toilets and showers in close proximity to the campsites.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Radio-Free Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Sandy Flats Campground provides a radio-free camping experience.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Roofed Accommodation</CampType>
                <CampDescription>A stunning lakeside retreat is waiting for you at Bonnechere. Along the shores of Round Lake, the Pine Shores Cottage is built and trimmed in pine and offers many comforts for a relaxing getaway.
                Bonnechere offers four Rustic Cabins for rent. Come and stay with us along the banks of the Bonnechere River while discovering a world of recreation close by. For those who are looking for a break away from the everyday, try sleeping under a solid roof in log beds. The cabins are set along the scenic Bonnechere River and are built and trimmed in pine lumber which gives them a warm, cozy, "rustic" experience.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Biking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Biking is an excellent way to get around the park and is encouraged by park staff. Biking is permitted along park roads. There are no designated bike trails.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Birding</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Bonnechere provides homes for many birds throughout the year and in fact, there are about 297 species that have been sighted in the area. A birding checklist is available at the park for a reasonable cost.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Boating</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Power boats are allowed on Round Lake and the Bonnechere River. Please be observe no wake speeds while traveling the river as it is home to many sensitive species and habitats.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Canoeing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Visitors to Bonnechere typically enjoy leisurely paddles along the meandering banks of the Bonnechere River from the park to Jack's Chute (~3km). Highlights include exploring the oxbows which are habitat for a variety of creatures big and small like turtles, fish, ducks and deer.

For a bit more adventure you can purchase a canoe route map for the Bonnechere River Provincial Park.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>The Bonnechere River and Round Lake provide opportunities for Large and Small Mouth Bass, pumpkinseed, Rock Bass, pike, pickerel and Lake Trout.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Hiking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>McNaugton Trail - 2 km (40 - 60 minutes) - Out and back to loop - Easy 
Take an easy stroll along the meandering Bonnechere River and learn about its rich natural and cultural history by exploring our Foot Prints in Time (FIT). FIT is based on the traditional local First Nations way of teaching and explaining our history. The trail takes you in stride with 13 giant foot prints, marked by posts with interpretive and educational text designed to be informative and engage you and your family along the hike. You will truly enjoy this adventure.

Walks of the Little Bonnechere River - 10 trails - varied lengths and difficulties
The Walks of the Little Bonnechere River is a compilation of 10 local trails and stopping places which will help you gain an understanding of the history of the river and its people. Each trail offers a variety of experiences and opportunities to explore natural and cultural history. Trail length and difficulty vary, providing an opportunity for all to enjoy. A booklet with maps, locations, pictures and descriptive text on these trails can be purchased at the park office at a reasonable cost.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Natural Heritage Education</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>During the summer, park staff offer a variety of fun, interactive educational programs. Join a park naturalist as you explore Footprints in Time at the hiking trail and the Visitor Centre. Bring your young campers to the children's programs and take the whole family to the evening campfires, slide shows and the many unique presentations and entertainment.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>There is one beautiful sandy beach at Bonnechere that is recommended for swimming. The Main Beach is located in the day-use area near the Visitor Centre and Park Store and is located on the shores of Round Lake. The beach is marked with buoys and has shallow gradual drop-offs. Please note: there are no lifeguards posted at the beach and pets are not permitted in the swimming area.

Pets can swim at the boat launch.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Barrier Free</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Available at the centrally comfort station as well as campsite #37.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Boat Launch</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The boat launch is located in the day-use area on the Bonnechere River. The maximum recommended size is 18 feet. Please contact park staff to discuss your particular situation if you have questions.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Comfort Station(s)</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>A full service comfort station is centrally located which provides access to flush toilets, showers and laundry facilities.

A mini-comfort station is located in Sandy Flats Campground which provides pedal flush toilets and shower stalls. There are no laundry facilities at this location.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The beach at the day-use area is popular for swimming.  A beautiful sandy beach with buoyed swimming area, a board walk and shady areas with picnic tables are the highlights.  There are no lifeguards posted at the beach.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Flush Toilets</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Available at the centrally located comfort station and the mini comfort station in Sandy Flats Campground.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Laundromat</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Two washers and Two dryers are available at the centrally located comfort station.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Park Store</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Located in the day-use area at the Davenport Centre. The store sells camper supplies such as utensils and tablecloths, ice and ice cream, drinks and snacks, Ontario Parks merchandise, firewood and Friends of Bonnechere Parks merchandise. Canoe and kayak rentals are provided at the Park Store.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Rentals</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Canoes and kayaks are rented out of the Park Store on a first-come first-served basis. Reservations are not taken.

Personal Floatation Devices (PFDs) are also available with a $25 refundable deposit.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Visitor Centre</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The Davenport Centre is located in the day-use area and is in the same building as the Park Store. Here you can participate in one of our many Natural Heritage programs and learn about Bonnechere's rich history linked to First Nations, pioneer and logging eras as well as the many natural features unique to the area.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
        <Park>
        <Name>Bronte Creek</Name>
        <Size>682.23</Size>
        <Location>
            <Latitude>43.40684</Latitude>
            <Longitude>-79.76889</Longitude>
        </Location>
        <OpenDateRange>
            <OpenDate>April 1, 2016</OpenDate>
            <CloseDate>October 23, 2016</CloseDate>
        </OpenDateRange>
        <URL>http://ontarioparks.com/park/brontecreek</URL>
        <Camps>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Car Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Bronte Creek offers car camping in all four of the campground loops. The Prairie loop is designed to accommodate larger RV's but will easily accommodate smaller trailers or tents as well. The Savannah, Woodlands and Ravine Loops are ideal for smaller trailers less than 25 ft and tent camping. All campsites have electrical hook up for each campsite. Amenities such as water taps, comfort stations, laundry facilities, playgrounds, hiking trails and amphitheater are close by. Day-use facilities are a short drive outside of the park.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Group Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Bronte Creek offers four group campsites.  These sites will accommodate up to 25 people. The sites are only accessed by a short walking path from the parking lots. The sites do not accommodate any type of vehicle or trailer and do not offer electricity. Water taps and small washroom facilities are located near by.

To reserve, please call 1-888-ONT-PARK (1-888-668-7275) or 1-519-826-5290 outside of North America.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Radio-Free Camping</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Savannah Loop is radio free.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
            <Camp>
                <CampType>Roofed Accommodation</CampType>
                <CampDescription>Bronte Creek offers three yurts for rent. All three are located in the Savannah Loop which is designated as radio free.</CampDescription>
            </Camp>
        </Camps>
        <Acivities>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Biking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Maiden's Blush Trail allows cycling and there are many gravel road and access trails to bike throughout the park.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Birding</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Bronte Creek Provincial Park, with its open fields, is a favourite of many birds of prey, hawks, merlin, kestrels and eagles. Not to mention various species of owls. The park has been known to be home to over 190 species of birds.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Fishing</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>You can access the creek easily by following Half Moon Valley Trail. Once there you may fish (in season) for Rainbow Trout, splake, steelhead and Pacific Salmon.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Hiking</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Maiden's Blush Trail - 1 km - (Located in Day-Use Area)
The trailhead is north of the Children's Playbarn (Lot C). This paved trail winds through mature forest and is suitable for walking, roller blading and cycling. This trail is wheelchair accessible.

Trillium Trail - 1 km - (Located in Day-Use Area)
The trailhead located behind the barns of Spruce Lane Farm (Lot F). This trail is the best place in the park to see spring wildflowers and catch a breathtaking glimpse of the valley floor. The trail is wheelchair and stroller friendly.

Ravine Trail - 2.7 km- (Located in Day-Use Area) 
This linear path meanders along the top of the valley between Spruce Lane Farm and the picnic area by Parking Lot A. (access via Lot A or F)

Gateway Trail - 1.5 km- (located in Campground area)

Halfmoon Valley Trail - 2km (Located in Day-Use Area)
Trailhead is minutes from Spruce Lane Farmhouse (lot F). Explore the Bronte Creek valley and the parks early history. It includes some steep climbs and may not be suitable for disabled visitors. MP3 audio tour available.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Natural Heritage Education</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Bronte Creek Provincial Park offers two interpretive centres. Spruce Lane Farmhouse, located close to parking lot F in the day-use area, showcases what life for the early farmer (1890 -1905) must have been like. Many demonstrations and special events highlight this one-of-a-kind living history museum.

The Nature Centre is located next to the big Red Play Barn and Children's Farm. Displays feature the unique natural elements of the park: ravine and creek, field and forest. Kids love to visit with our turtles and explore hands-on in our discovery room. Many daily programs in the summer start here at the Nature Centre.

Family programs and events are offered March through to December.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Swimming</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Bronte Creek Provincial Park is home to one of Canada's largest outdoor pools. This 1.8 acre pool is located at the Recreation Complex in the Day-Use area. The pool is a large pond shape that is designed for wading with a starting depth of mere centimeters, gradually deepening to 2 m (6 ft) in the center. Lifeguards are on duty. (There is an additional fee to use the pool area.) Pool Season : last Saturday in June to Labour Day. (temporary closures may occur due to weather).</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
            <Activity>
                <AcivityType>Winter Activities</AcivityType>
                <ActivityDescription>Weather permitting: the park maintains an Olympic-size skating rink (located at Recreation Complex) from mid December until Family Day in February. There is also a toboggan hill and approximately 5 km of cross-country ski trails that loop throughout the park.</ActivityDescription>
            </Activity>
        </Acivities>
        <Facilities>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Barrier Free</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Maiden's Blush Trail is barrier-free. All washroom facilities have barrier-free access. There are two campsites designated as barrier-free.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Comfort Station(s)</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Our Day-Use Area has nine comfort stations with running water and flush toilets.

The two campground comfort stations are centrally located and equipped with running water, flush toilets, showers and coin operated laundry machines.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Day Use</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Bronte Creek offers day-use everyday of the year except Christmas day.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Flush Toilets</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>All washroom facilities at Bronte Creek are equipped with running water and flush toilets.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Laundromat</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Coin Laundry is available at the two comfort stations at the campground.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Park Store</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The park store is open from the last weekend in June until Labour Day and reopens for the skating season the 3rd weekend in December until the last weekend in February (weather permitting). The park store sells Ontario Parks merchandise and items that you may have forgotten when packing for your day outing. The store also sells fresh food concession items and sundries.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Pet Exercise Area</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The Park has two leash free areas; one is a .5 km loop located in the Day-Use area and one 2 km loop in the Campground.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Picnic Shelters</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>There are 11 picnic shelters available for rental between the 3rd weekend in June and the 2nd weekend in December. The shelters are first-come first-served for the remainder of the year. All shelters have large charcoal BBQ grills for use. (must supply own charcoal)</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Rentals</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>The park store offers skate and skate aid rentals in the winter and sport ball rentals in the summer.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
            <Facility>
                <FacilityType>Visitor Centre</FacilityType>
                <FacilityDescription>Bronte Creek has two visitor centres.

The Nature Centre is where visitors can learn about glaciers and wildlife or meet for special outings such as spirit walks or coyote howls.

Spruce Lane Farm House is the centre of the annual Maple Syrup Festival and Homestead Christmas Program. During the summer months you can chat with the staff in period costume about life in the early 1900s and witness some of the activities from that time.</FacilityDescription>
            </Facility>
        </Facilities>
    </Park>
</ParkList>